Guide to the Robert Truax Washington, D.C. transportation collection, 1880-1985
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Robert Truax Washington, D.C. transportation collection
1880-1985
C0273
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
6 linear feet (4 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
Collection consists of a variety of transportation-related documents, maps, and images. The most numerous group in the collection is approximately 150 postcards of Washington, D.C. from the early to mid-20th century, many of which include streetcars as well as famous streets and buildings.
Truax, Robert A.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Jeff Haggquist and Heidi Worley in August 2014.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center holds many other transportation-related collections.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject and date.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of a variety of transportation-related documents, maps, and images. There are 150 postcards of Washington, D.C. many of which include streetcars as well as famous streets and buildings. The collection also includes approximately 12 maps of Washington, D.C. street railway and bus routes from 1880 and the 1940s. There are rolling stock inventories from the 1930s and conductor leave of absence reports from the 1920s. There are also a small number of World War II letters unrelated to the rest of the collection. There are also two glass plate negatives approximately 6.5 x 8.5" that contain images of Luna Park in Arlington, Virginia, and a railroad track and train in Harper's Ferry Virginia. Both images date from around 1900 to 1915. There are also a small number of materials related the postal service and stamps. Finally, there are two oversize volumes: one volume of passenger receipts from 1909. and one volume of conductor receipts from 1898.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Washington, D.C.--Postcards.
Subjects:
Urban transportation.
Document Types:
Maps.; Postcards.
Contents List
- Glass plate negatives, circa 1905 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Maps and pamphlets, 1985 - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Motorman and conductor leave of absence logbook, 1921 - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Rolling stock and cars inventory, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Rolling stock and cars inventory, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Washington, D.C. postcards, circa 1900 - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Washington, D.C. postcards, circa 1900 - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Washington, D.C. postcards, circa 1900 - 1950s (Box 2, Folder 1)
- World War II letters, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Conductor receipts, 1898 (Box 3)
- Passenger receipts, 1909 (Box 4)
- Washington, D.C. street railway and bus route maps, 1880 - 1940s